<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FCP</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Football Culture</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 13:58:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/logo2-150x150.png</url>
	<title>FCP</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The 10 Most Shocking Football Transfers of All Time</title>
		<link>/the-10-most-shocking-football-transfers-of-all-time/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-10-most-shocking-football-transfers-of-all-time</link>
					<comments>/the-10-most-shocking-football-transfers-of-all-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot Fagan-Briggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 13:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[#Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The football world is no stranger to blockbuster transfers that shake things up and get fans buzzing. But every so often, a transfer deal comes along that truly shocks and rocks the sport. Whether it’s fierce rivals selling their best players to each other, record-breaking fees being paid, or controversial superstars switching sides unexpectedly, these [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-10-most-shocking-football-transfers-of-all-time/">The 10 Most Shocking Football Transfers of All Time</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The football world is no stranger to blockbuster transfers that shake things up and get fans buzzing. But every so often, a transfer deal comes along that truly shocks and rocks the sport. Whether it’s fierce rivals selling their best players to each other, record-breaking fees being paid, or controversial superstars switching sides unexpectedly, these moves make headlines and get people talking for years to come.</p>



<p>In this blog post, we take a look at 10 of the most earth-shattering and shocking transfers in football history. These are deals that came out of nowhere and caught supporters completely off guard. From world record fees to bitter betrayals to transfers that seemed unthinkable at the time, we countdown the biggest stunners ever seen in the beautiful game. Relive the surprise and disbelief sparked by these monumental transfers that no one saw coming. The sensational deals on this list caused jaws to drop and made people wonder “How did that just happen?”.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>10. Paul Pogba from Man United to Juventus (2012)</strong></h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/pogba-1024x576.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-190" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/pogba-1024x576.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/pogba-300x169.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/pogba-768x432.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/pogba-1536x864.jpeg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/pogba.jpeg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Sir Alex Ferguson was left shocked when teenage midfielder Paul Pogba decided to walk away from Manchester United on a free transfer to join Juventus in 2012. Pogba grew frustrated by his lack of playing time at Old Trafford and opted to move abroad to gain more first-team opportunities. United fans were outraged that such a promising young talent was allowed to leave for nothing, especially when Pogba began fulfilling his immense potential in Serie A. His departure was the beginning of the fractured relationship between Pogba and Ferguson, who later stated his biggest management regret was not giving Pogba more of a chance to develop at United. Juventus gained a future superstar for free while United lost one, making it one of the most shocking transfers of money left on the table.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>9. Ronaldinho from PSG to Barcelona (2003)</strong></h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" width="720" height="405" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ronaldinho.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-191" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ronaldinho.webp 720w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/ronaldinho-300x169.webp 300w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></figure>



<p>Barcelona pulled off a transfer coup in 2003 by signing Brazilian superstar Ronaldinho from Paris Saint-Germain for €30 million. Ronaldinho had shone at the 2002 World Cup, establishing himself as one of the most exciting talents in world football. His shock move to Barça came after Manchester United had failed to land the Brazilian earlier that summer. At the time, Barcelona were rebuilding after some lean years but Ronaldinho’s arrival signaled a change in fortune. His flair, skill, and infectious smile ushered in Barça’s era of dominance under Frank Rijkaard. Ronaldinho became a Camp Nou legend, leading Barcelona to back-to-back La Liga titles and their first Champions League in 14 years. Capturing his signature transformed the club’s fortunes, making this transfer a monumental and shocking turning point.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>8. Andy Carroll from Newcastle to Liverpool (2011)</strong></h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/andy-carroll-1024x576.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-192" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/andy-carroll-1024x576.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/andy-carroll-300x169.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/andy-carroll-768x432.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/andy-carroll.jpeg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>On deadline day in January 2011, Liverpool pulled off one of the most shocking and expensive transfers in their history by signing Newcastle striker Andy Carroll for £35 million. This astonishingly high fee came mere hours after Liverpool had sold Fernando Torres to Chelsea for £50 million. Spending such a huge sum to replace Torres with Carroll, who had only shown glimpses of his potential, left many scratching their heads. The young English striker struggled with injuries and form at Anfield, scoring just 11 goals in 58 games before being loaned and eventually sold at a £20 million loss for Liverpool. Carroll’s exorbitant price tag and subsequent failure to deliver made this one of the most confusing and shocking transfer decisions, especially under the pressure of a deadline day.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>7. David Beckham from Man United to Real Madrid (2003)</strong></h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="538" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/beckham-1024x538.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-193" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/beckham-1024x538.webp 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/beckham-300x158.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/beckham-768x403.webp 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/beckham-1536x806.webp 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/beckham.webp 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>David Beckham sent shockwaves through the football world when he left Manchester United to join Spanish giants Real Madrid in 2003. Beckham had become a global superstar at Old Trafford, helping United win six Premier League titles. However, his relationship with manager Sir Alex Ferguson deteriorated after an infamous dressing room incident. When Madrid came calling with a €35 million bid, Ferguson agreed to sell the England captain. Beckham’s departure rocked United fans while Madrid rejoiced signing one of football’s most marketable players ever. Beckham may have achieved more success at United but he become an icon in Madrid. His first Galactico signing ushered in Madrid’s era of lavish spending on superstar players, making this a landmark transfer that massively shocked football.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>6. Carlos Tevez and Javier Mascherano to West Ham (2006)</strong></h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="489" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/tevez-mascherano-1024x489.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-194" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/tevez-mascherano-1024x489.webp 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/tevez-mascherano-300x143.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/tevez-mascherano-768x367.webp 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/tevez-mascherano-1536x734.webp 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/tevez-mascherano-2048x979.webp 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Two of South America’s biggest superstars, Carlos Tevez and Javier Mascherano, shocked world football by joining West Ham United in 2006. In a deadline day double deal, the Argentine duo signed for the struggling Premier League club from Brazilian team Corinthians. It was seen as a bizarre move for two players of such calibre to leave high profile clubs in South America to join West Ham, who were battling relegation. The transfers were facilitated by businessman Kia Joorabchian and were mired in controversy regarding third party ownership. Nevertheless, Tevez would go onto score the vital goals to keep West Ham up, endearing himself to fans. While Mascherano quickly departed for Liverpool, the shock arrivals of these two Argentina interntionals briefly made West Ham the talk of world football.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>5. Ashley Cole from Arsenal to Chelsea (2006)</strong></h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="551" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/cole-1024x551.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-195" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/cole-1024x551.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/cole-300x161.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/cole-768x413.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/cole.jpeg 1451w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>England left-back Ashley Cole caused outrage when he moved directly from Arsenal to rivals Chelsea in 2006 for £5 million and William Gallas. Cole had come up through the Arsenal academy but was part of the ‘Invincibles’ side. However, after a tapping up scandal, where Chelsea were fined for illegally approaching Cole, the defender quickly pushed for a move. Arsenal fans labelled Cole ‘Cashley’ and a traitor for forcing his way out to a direct rival. The controversial transfer shocked football given Cole’s status at Arsenal and the tense rivalry with Chelsea. Cole would go on to win further honours at Stamford Bridge, establishing himself as one of the world’s best left-backs. But his acrimonious departure from North London severed his Arsenal legacy, making him a hated figure amongst Gunners’ fans.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>4. Luis Enrique from Real Madrid to Barcelona (1996)</strong></h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/enrique-1024x576.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-196" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/enrique-1024x576.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/enrique-300x169.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/enrique-768x432.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/enrique.jpeg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>In a rare transfer between the bitter El Clasico rivals, Luis Enrique made a controversial switch directly from Real Madrid to Barcelona in 1996. The Spanish midfielder had come through Madrid’s youth system and played over 100 games for their first team. Moving directly to Barcelona was almost unheard of between the fiercely partisan clubs. Barcelona paid around £3 million to activate Enrique’s release clause, shocking Madrid fans. However, Enrique became a key player under Bobby Robson and Louis van Gaal, winning 2 consecutive La Ligas and the Copa del Rey. He endeared himself to Culés and scored against Los Blancos in his first Clasico appearance. While cross-city switches are more common nowadays, Enrique’s controversial transfer paved the way and shocked Spanish football at the time.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>3. Sol Campbell from Tottenham to Arsenal (2001)</strong></h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/campbell-1024x576.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-197" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/campbell-1024x576.webp 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/campbell-300x169.webp 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/campbell-768x432.webp 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/campbell-1536x864.webp 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/campbell-2048x1152.webp 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Sol Campbell caused outrage in 2001 when he crossed the North London divide to join rivals Arsenal on a free transfer from Tottenham. As Spurs captain, Campbell was a fan favorite during his 10 years there. His departure to Arsenal stunned the football world given the intense rivalry between the two clubs. Spurs fans branded Campbell ‘Judas’ and a traitor for the shock move. Campbell proved critics wrong as he formed a legendary partnership with Tony Adams, winning 2 Premier League titles and 3 FA Cups with the Gunners. However, he forever ruined his reputation with Spurs supporters in an instant by joining their most despised rivals. The controversy and outrage sparked by Campbell’s transfer made it one of the most shocking moves in Premier League history.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>2. Robinho from Real Madrid to Manchester City (2008)</strong></h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/robinho.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-198" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/robinho.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/robinho-300x169.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/robinho-768x432.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Manchester City had already shocked football by being bought by Abu Dhabi owners, but the lavish spending reached new heights in 2008. On the same day Sheikh Mansour completed his City takeover, the club smashed the British transfer record to sign Brazilian star Robinho from Real Madrid for £32.5 million. Robinho was regarded as one of the most skillful wingers in the world during his time at Madrid. For him to leave the Santiago Bernabeu to join the Premier League’s perennial underachievers was astounding. City supporters could barely believe Robinho was wearing sky blue at the time. This mega-money transfer announced City’s arrival as a major force, backed by the immense wealth of their new owners. Signing a world-class talent like Robinho was a significant statement of intent that shocked football.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>1. Luis Figo from Barcelona to Real Madrid (2000)</strong></h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/figo-1024x576.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-199" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/figo-1024x576.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/figo-300x169.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/figo-768x432.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/figo-1536x864.jpeg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/11/figo.jpeg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>The world record €62 million transfer of Luis Figo from Barcelona to arch-rivals Real Madrid in 2000 sent shockwaves through football. Figo was a beloved star at the Camp Nou, winning two La Liga titles, two Copa del Reys, and the UEFA Cup Winners’ Cup. However, Real Madrid triggered Figo’s record release clause and he made the controversial switch to the Bernabeu. Barcelona fans felt utterly betrayed and greeted Figo’s return with Barcelona with deafening boos and pig heads thrown on the pitch. The transfer fee was unprecedented at the time and Figo’s direct move embittered El Clasico forever. The Galacticos era was born at Madrid as Perez began his mission to assemble the world’s best players. While the move brought Figo success, he forever ruined his Barcelona legacy in an act of betrayal that will never be forgotten.</p>



<p>The football transfers on this list shocked supporters and transformed clubs in an instant. Each one had its fair share of controversy, outrage and disbelief when they were announced. From Sol Campbell’s bitter betrayal to Robinho’s mega-money deadline day transfer, these moves came out of nowhere to stun fans. Luis Figo’s world record switch to Real Madrid tops our list as the most shocking transfer ever seen, sparking a new era of spending in football.</p>



<p>While other sports have seen their fair share of controversies, football transfers evoke raw passion and emotion like no other. Fans view their clubs as lifelong allegiances rather than franchises, making these controversial player moves cut deep. The outrage, bitterness and ensuing drama is what makes the transfer market so utterly engrossing for football fans. These ten transfers will forever be remembered for their unbelievable, earth-shattering shock value that left the football world speechless.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/the-10-most-shocking-football-transfers-of-all-time/">The 10 Most Shocking Football Transfers of All Time</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-10-most-shocking-football-transfers-of-all-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unleash Your Inner Football Gossipmonger with the Transfer Rumour Generator</title>
		<link>/unleash-your-inner-football-gossipmonger-with-the-transfer-rumour-generator/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=unleash-your-inner-football-gossipmonger-with-the-transfer-rumour-generator</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot Fagan-Briggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 08:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[#Sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=174</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Are you an ardent football fanatic who lives and breathes transfer rumors? Do you thrive on the adrenaline-pumping excitement of sensational transfers that keep the football world abuzz? If so, we&#8217;ve got a fantastic treat for you! Check out the Transfer Rumour Generator, your go-to destination for generating random football transfer rumors that are sure [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/unleash-your-inner-football-gossipmonger-with-the-transfer-rumour-generator/">Unleash Your Inner Football Gossipmonger with the Transfer Rumour Generator</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Are you an ardent football fanatic who lives and breathes transfer rumors? Do you thrive on the adrenaline-pumping excitement of sensational transfers that keep the football world abuzz? If so, we&#8217;ve got a fantastic treat for you! Check out the <a href="/transfer-rumour-generator/">Transfer Rumour Generator</a>, your go-to destination for generating random football transfer rumors that are sure to leave your friends and social media followers in stitches or shock!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What Is The Transfer Rumour Generator?</strong></h2>



<p>The Transfer Rumour Generator is your passport to the fascinating world of football transfer gossip. It&#8217;s a tool that&#8217;s been designed to make you the ultimate football pundit, allowing you to create and share random transfer rumors effortlessly.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How Does It Work?</strong></h2>



<p>Our transfer rumor generator is a simple yet ingenious tool that randomly crafts transfer stories, making you feel like a real football insider. Here&#8217;s how it works:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Player Selection</strong>: The generator randomly picks the name of a footballer. It could be Messi, Ronaldo, Neymar, or any other player from the global football roster.</li>



<li><strong>Club Association</strong>: The magic doesn&#8217;t stop there. The tool then randomly selects a football club that the player is &#8220;linked&#8221; with. Imagine the endless possibilities – Ronaldo moving to a Championship club or Messi joining a non-existent team. The excitement is boundless!</li>



<li><strong>Transfer Fee</strong>: Lastly, Transferrumourgenerator.online throws in the element of surprise by choosing a random transfer fee ranging from £0 to a jaw-dropping £100 million.</li>
</ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why You&#8217;ll Love Our Transfer Rumour Generator</strong></h2>



<ol>
<li><strong>Endless Entertainment</strong>: Let&#8217;s face it – transfer rumors are a guilty pleasure for football enthusiasts. With our generator, you can create and share rumors that are as wild and unpredictable as your imagination allows.</li>



<li><strong>Light-Hearted Banter</strong>: There&#8217;s nothing like sharing an absurd transfer rumor with your football-crazy buddies. It&#8217;s the perfect conversation starter, and it&#8217;s all in good fun.</li>
</ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Get Started!</strong></h2>



<p>Are you ready to dive into the world of bizarre transfer rumors, or are you eager to explore intriguing football articles? Don&#8217;t hesitate; head over to our Transfer Rumour Generator and let the fun begin!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/unleash-your-inner-football-gossipmonger-with-the-transfer-rumour-generator/">Unleash Your Inner Football Gossipmonger with the Transfer Rumour Generator</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stormzy brings back Merky FC for a new season</title>
		<link>/stormzy-brings-back-merky-fc-for-a-new-season/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=stormzy-brings-back-merky-fc-for-a-new-season</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot Fagan-Briggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 10:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[#Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adidas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merky FC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stormzy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Stormzy has once again teamed up with adidas to launch #Merky FC Football Careers Season 2, an initiative aimed at creating leadership opportunities in football for the Black community. The program was originally created in response to the fact that currently only 6.7% of leadership positions in football are held by those with Black heritage. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/stormzy-brings-back-merky-fc-for-a-new-season/">Stormzy brings back Merky FC for a new season</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Stormzy has once again teamed up with adidas to launch #Merky FC Football Careers Season 2, an initiative aimed at creating leadership opportunities in football for the Black community.</strong></p>



<p>The program was originally created in response to the fact that currently only 6.7% of leadership positions in football are held by those with Black heritage. Through <a href="https://merkyfc.com/">#Merky FC Football Careers</a>, Stormzy and adidas hope to address the lack of fair access and representation for Black individuals looking to build careers in the sport.</p>



<p>The multi-year partnership will provide a career development program and job placements across various roles in football, at various businesses including professional football clubs and media outlets.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignwide size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="670" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/IMG_6603-1024x670.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-153" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/IMG_6603-1024x670.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/IMG_6603-300x196.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/IMG_6603-768x503.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/IMG_6603.jpg 1170w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The brands and businesses working with Adidas and Merky FC this year</figcaption></figure>



<p>The first season of placements under #Merky FC Football Careers launched in November 2022 with 11 major brands participating. 15 Young black people from the UK earned jobs in the football industry as a result of Merky FC, and this year the second season will kick off in October 2023 with over 50 new placement opportunities.</p>



<p>Stormzy said &#8220;There&#8217;s still a massive gap in representation off the pitch&#8221;. He hopes the program will &#8220;create long-lasting change&#8221; and build a pipeline of future Black leaders in football. <a href="https://www.adidas.co.uk/football">Adidas</a> emphasized the importance of diversity and equal representation at all levels of the sport.</p>



<p>The initiative is the latest effort by Stormzy and adidas to increase inclusion and accessibility in football. Both have been outspoken advocates for racial equality in sport and society.</p>



<p>Watch the video below:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed aligncenter is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Merky?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Merky</a> FC is back, but this year, we&#39;ve got to go bigger.<br><br>Share one of the 50 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MerkyFC?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MerkyFC</a> roles with a friend now to change the game. <a href="https://t.co/pllMjqO5zv">https://t.co/pllMjqO5zv</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/adidasfootball?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@adidasfootball</a> <a href="https://t.co/qXSodEy07V">pic.twitter.com/qXSodEy07V</a></p>&mdash; Stormzy (@stormzy) <a href="https://twitter.com/stormzy/status/1709846452342501827?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2023</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="/stormzy-brings-back-merky-fc-for-a-new-season/">Stormzy brings back Merky FC for a new season</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From the Pitch to Politics: Gary Neville&#8217;s Transition to Political Commentary</title>
		<link>/from-the-pitch-to-politics-gary-nevilles-transition-to-political-commentary/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=from-the-pitch-to-politics-gary-nevilles-transition-to-political-commentary</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot Fagan-Briggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 09:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[#Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gary Neville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Once best known for his stellar football career, Gary Neville has recently grabbed headlines for his outspoken views on politics and social issues. The former Manchester United defender has never been shy about sharing his opinions, whether as a broadcaster or on social media. But his decision to join the Labour Party in January 2023 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/from-the-pitch-to-politics-gary-nevilles-transition-to-political-commentary/">From the Pitch to Politics: Gary Neville&#8217;s Transition to Political Commentary</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Once best known for his stellar football career, Gary Neville has recently grabbed headlines for his outspoken views on politics and social issues. The former Manchester United defender has never been shy about sharing his opinions, whether as a broadcaster or on social media. But his decision to join the Labour Party in January 2023 signaled a shift to becoming an active participant in politics.</strong></p>



<p>Neville&#8217;s footballing CV is impeccable &#8211; over 600 appearances for Manchester United, winning eight Premier League titles, three FA Cups, and two Champions Leagues. He was also England&#8217;s first-choice right-back for a decade, earning 85 caps. Since retiring in 2011, Neville has become a leading football pundit on Sky Sports and ITV. His frank, thoughtful analysis has earned him a reputation as the top commentator in the game.</p>



<p>Outside football, Neville has been vocal about poverty, sexism, racism, and the need to reform football governance. He has regularly criticized Boris Johnson&#8217;s government over their policies. But the move to officially join Labour has put Neville&#8217;s left-leaning politics into action. He has spoken of his ambition to influence policy debates and play a role in shaping Labour&#8217;s direction.</p>



<p>For many, Neville seems an unlikely political crusader. But his journey from the pitch to political activism reflects how some leading sports figures are choosing to use their profile to drive social change. As he sets out on this new path, all eyes will be on Neville to see if he can score key goals outside the sporting arena.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">From Player to Politico</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6576-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-136" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6576-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6576-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6576-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6576-1536x864.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6576.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Gary Neville giving a speech (Image via Football365)</figcaption></figure>



<p>Neville publicly announced that he had joined the Labour Party in January 2023, saying he wanted to support the party after being impressed by leader Keir Starmer. This step formalized political allegiances that had been clear for some time from Neville&#8217;s commentary.</p>



<p>Throughout 2022, Neville was outspoken in his criticisms of Boris Johnson&#8217;s government over issues like parties during lockdown at Downing Street. He labeled ministers as &#8220;corrupt&#8221; and called for Johnson to resign. On social matters, Neville has backed football players taking the knee against racism. And he has argued for more taxation on the wealthy.</p>



<p>Neville has made the case that wealthy people like himself should contribute more. He supports Starmer&#8217;s policy of putting the top income tax rate back up to 50% for those earning over £125,000, a threshold encompassing Neville&#8217;s own earnings. The former footballer has also endorsed increased windfall taxes on the profits of energy companies.</p>



<p>On economic issues, Neville has praised Labour&#8217;s calls for increased public investment and for a strengthened social safety net. He has said he believes in the role of unions to represent workers. And he has criticized Sunak&#8217;s Government for being &#8220;anti-worker.&#8221;</p>



<p>Some see Neville&#8217;s motivations stemming from his close ties to Manchester and the inequalities he has seen in the city. He seems driven by a belief in using his wealth and public profile as a force for good. And he has hinted his new party membership is just the start of an active political role.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Broadcasting Platform</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6577-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-137" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6577-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6577-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6577-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6577.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Gary Neville appearing on Monday Night Football (Image via Sky Sports)</figcaption></figure>



<p>After hanging up his boots in 2011, Gary Neville soon transitioned into a prominent football punditry role with Sky Sports. His incisive, straight-talking analysis earned him plaudits and huge popularity with viewers.</p>



<p>Neville&#8217;s articles and podcasts also display his keen intellect &#8211; he gained a degree in Sports Science and Business Management in his playing days. Nevile has leveraged his broadcasting platform not just to discuss tactics and results, but increasingly to share his views on political and social issues.</p>



<p>On Sky&#8217;s Monday Night Football, Neville has used segments to argue against racism in football and society. And he has weighed in on controversies like the European Super League breakaway attempt. His high-profile likely gives his political messaging far more reach than the average pundit.</p>



<p>Neville has shown he won&#8217;t shy away from criticizing political leaders, no matter their affiliation. He condemned Boris Johnson for not resigning sooner amid partygate. And he has chastised Keir Starmer for not voicing stronger opposition on key issues.</p>



<p>This independent streak has earned Neville some backlash, but also respect for avoiding partisanship. And it suggests he won&#8217;t just toe the party line if elected. Neville has said he won&#8217;t abandon his &#8220;impartiality&#8221; as a broadcaster despite joining Labour.</p>



<p>With 5 million Twitter followers and a prime TV slot, Neville will likely continue using his broadcasting profile as a powerful platform. As he becomes more active in Labour politics, his outspoken takes on the issues of the day will be harder to ignore.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Following in Familiar Footsteps</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6578-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-138" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6578-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6578-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6578-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6578-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6578-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Cyrille Regis was a big campaigner against Racism in Football (Image via The Times)</figcaption></figure>



<p>While Gary Neville is one of the most prominent recent soccer stars to wade into politics, he follows a path blazed by several ex-players before him. The crossover from pitch to parliament shows how some aim to take their influence into public service after exiting sport.</p>



<p>One of the earliest high-profile cases was Cyrille Regis &#8211; the West Brom striker was a pioneering Black footballer in the 1970s and 80s before joining the Labour Party upon retirement. Regis served as a councillor in his hometown of Coventry and worked to tackle racism in the game.</p>



<p>Former Ireland and Arsenal player David O&#8217;Leary had a brief stint as a Conservative MP in 2002, utilizing his fame to get elected. And ex-England goalkeeper David James ran unsuccessfully as a Conservative council candidate in 2019 on a platform opposing a new stadium development.</p>



<p>The most successful politician offspring has been former Chelsea winger Wycombe Wanderers&#8217; mayor Peter Taylor. The long-serving councillor became the mayor of the town where his club is based in 2018.</p>



<p>Internationally, examples like George Weah of Liberia and Romario of Brazil show how ex-players have risen to head government ministries or even become president. Their sporting credentials and fame helped elevate their political profiles.</p>



<p>As Neville follows in these footsteps, his fellow footballers-turned-politicians provide models to emulate &#8211; and cautionary tales to avoid &#8211; in seeking to make an impact. Their mixed results show both the potential rewards and risks that come with moving from the locker room to the corridors of power.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Lessons from the Pitch to Parliament</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1000" height="667" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6579.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-139" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6579.jpg 1000w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6579-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6579-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">House of Commons (Image via gov.uk)</figcaption></figure>



<p>The paths of former players like Cyrille Regis and Romario demonstrate how transferring sporting profile into politics can bring extra attention and credibility. But the results have been mixed when it comes to achieving lasting policy change.</p>



<p>Regis took on an important role speaking out against racism in the game, using his reputation to influence attitudes. However, his impact as a Labour councillor was limited by staying at the local level. Romario gained hype as a congressman but ultimately did not run for re-election.</p>



<p>Ex-players often command respect immediately due to their sporting resumes. But critics argue they rarely put in the work required to gain expertise on complex policy issues. Gary Neville will need to demonstrate a deeper understanding of the workings of government to be taken seriously.</p>



<p>Staying on message is also key — O’Leary’s stint as an MP fizzled out quickly when he seemed more interested in photo ops than serving constituents. And David James&#8217; anti-stadium campaign smacked of opportunism to some.</p>



<p>One lesson is the need to pay dues with party activism before seeking office. Wycombe&#8217;s Peter Taylor built up decades of service before becoming mayor. Neville will need to avoid perceptions of simply leveraging his celebrity.</p>



<p>As Neville follows in their footsteps, he’ll have to prove his motivations go beyond vanity and tap into his sporting discipline. The path from locker room to parliament is filled with pitfalls. But the ex-Man United man has never shied away from a challenge on or off the pitch.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Prospects on the Campaign Trail</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="464" height="278" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6580.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-140" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6580.jpg 464w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6580-300x180.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 464px) 100vw, 464px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Gary Neville speaking at a Labour Party Conference (Image via The Guardian)</figcaption></figure>



<p>If Gary Neville decides to run for elected office, either as an MP or a local councillor, what are his chances of success? His fame and resources would be significant advantages, but also potential liabilities.</p>



<p>On the positive side, Neville would receive wall-to-wall media coverage focusing on his candidacy. His name recognition is higher than virtually any other potential candidate. And with deep pockets, Neville could amply fund advertising and staff.</p>



<p>However, his lack of political experience could be viewed as a weakness by some voters. Rivals may attack him as an out-of-touch celebrity seeking power and fame. Maintaining discipline on the campaign trail will be critical.</p>



<p>Neville&#8217;s best bet would likely be running in his native Greater Manchester, where his local credentials and support for the region are well-established. He might aim for a safe Labour seat or local council ward.</p>



<p>But his close association with rival city Liverpool through footballing clashes could hamper wider support. And an urban seat with student and minority voters may prefer a non-celebrity candidate.</p>



<p>Much depends on how seriously Neville is willing to put in the work &#8211; pounding the pavement, fundraising, building alliances with activists. He can&#8217;t rely on name recognition alone.</p>



<p>While the path from punditry to parliament won&#8217;t be easy, Neville has overcome long odds before. With the right team and strategy, his political prospects can&#8217;t be counted out. But he will have to demonstrate true commitment to public service over his own ego.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="976" height="549" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6581.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-141" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6581.jpg 976w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6581-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/img_6581-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 976px) 100vw, 976px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Gary Neville with Labour Party Leader Kier Starmer (Image via the BBC)</figcaption></figure>



<p>Gary Neville&#8217;s decision to join Labour and become politically active has opened a new chapter for the former football star. His outspoken commentary and social media presence already leverage his profile, but seeking elected office would take things to a new level.</p>



<p>Neville follows a well-worn path of athletes aiming to influence issues they care about beyond the arena of competition. Some have achieved noteworthy success, while others have found politics isn&#8217;t as easy as anticipated. Maintaining authenticity and putting in the work will be critical tests for Neville.</p>



<p>Above all, Neville&#8217;s second act highlights the platform that high-profile figures like him have to drive change on important issues. At a time of economic hardship and widening inequality, Neville has made clear he wants to be part of the solution.</p>



<p>If he can translate even a fraction of his footballing dexterity, leadership and determination into the political sphere, Neville has the potential to impact policy debates and be a force for good. His path from Old Trafford to Whitehall faces major obstacles, but will be compelling to watch unfold.</p>



<p>For now, Gary Neville&#8217;s political activism reflects a willingness to contest a very different kind of high-stakes game to achieve positive change off the pitch. Where it ultimately leads depends greatly on Neville&#8217;s own willingness to put in the hard yards necessary.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/from-the-pitch-to-politics-gary-nevilles-transition-to-political-commentary/">From the Pitch to Politics: Gary Neville&#8217;s Transition to Political Commentary</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Ten Hag running out of excuses?</title>
		<link>/is-ten-hag-running-out-of-excuses/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=is-ten-hag-running-out-of-excuses</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chris Cheetham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 09:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[#Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Man United]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ten Hag]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=126</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There are many underlying issues at Old Trafford that could be a factor in the poor start to the season they have had. Not all of them can be blamed on Erik Ten Hag, but each one only adds to the pressure facing the United coach. Let’s take a look at some of the problems [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/is-ten-hag-running-out-of-excuses/">Is Ten Hag running out of excuses?</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>There are many underlying issues at Old Trafford that could be a factor in the poor start to the season they have had. Not all of them can be blamed on Erik Ten Hag, but each one only adds to the pressure facing the United coach. Let’s take a look at some of the problems and assess Ten Hag’s response to them</strong>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Drama off the pitch</h3>



<p>First of all, United’s off field problems continue to grow. Having shifted Greenwood off to Getafe, Ten Hag had no rest as it was straight into the next scandal, this time involving Ten Hag’s big signing last summer Anthony. He has been “removed” from the squad for the time being. Ex-United captain Harry Maguire still lingers around Carrington training ground, proving that United cannot remove deadwood as easy as Erik would like. And the latest scandal involves Erik Ten Hag publicly criticising Jason Sancho and the star taking to Social Media to respond. The latest rumour swirling is that several stars where involved in a bust up after the defeat to Brighton. Whilst Ten Hag can’t be held accountable for the off field drama, how he handles this crisis will be critical in defining his United era.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Transfer Business</h3>



<p>After a 4-0 thrashing by Liverpool two seasons ago United interim manager Ralf Rangnick said that up to 10 new players were needed for the club&#8217;s impending rebuild. Fast forward to the start of this season and 10 permanent signings (and plenty of loans) later, has Erik Ten Hag managed to get in the players to make a meaningful Impression? The simple answer is yes, they are tactically adapted to ETH’s style, but so far this season it is those same signings that are letting the side down. Varane has spent more time on the injury list than the pitch, Casemiro is showing his age, Onana has had a rocky start, Mount has been non-existent, and without a doubt the loan signings during Erik’s time have been abysmal. The sole blame cannot be placed with Ten Hag, with recruitment at United being notorious for failing to get the top target, and over spending for those that they do sign.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="885" height="565" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/image-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-125" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/image-1.jpg 885w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/image-1-300x192.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/image-1-768x490.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 885px) 100vw, 885px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Image via ManUtd.com</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Performances and Results</h3>



<p>The most disappointing part of Ten Hag’s second season has been the performances. Despite all the signings to suit his tactic style, this has not been translated into the pitch. The players are acting as individuals, both attacking sense and when defending. Even the only wins this season against Wolves and Forest came against the run of play. Small glimpses of good play have given fans hope, but this is often met with poor sloppy play. This is something that will define Erik Ten Hag’s era at United. They need to shake it off and start playing progressive, pressing football that ETH is known for.</p>



<p>When Ten Hag took over he threatened to unsettle the duo of Klopp and Pep at the top of the table, but it is the teams in the Championship that will be most worried at this point in time. The next few weeks will be pivotal for Erik and his group of players. With tricky away ties to Bayern and Burnley on the cards, before a double header at home with Crystal Palace, Erik Ten Hag will be lucky to make it to the next international break.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/is-ten-hag-running-out-of-excuses/">Is Ten Hag running out of excuses?</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Football Manager is coming to Netflix</title>
		<link>/football-manager-is-coming-to-netflix/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=football-manager-is-coming-to-netflix</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot Fagan-Briggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 14:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[#Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Football Manager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The latest instalment of the award winning series, Football Manager, is coming to Netflix. Developers Sports Interactive announced today that their mobile version of the game, FM24 Mobile will be coming to Netflix gaming on November 6th. If you have a Netflix membership you can play the game via the Netflix mobile app, and you [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/football-manager-is-coming-to-netflix/">Football Manager is coming to Netflix</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The latest instalment of the award winning series, Football Manager, is coming to Netflix.</p>



<p>Developers <em>Sports Interactive</em> announced <a href="https://www.footballmanager.com/news/football-manager-2024-mobile-coming-exclusively-netflix">today</a> that their mobile version of the game, FM24 Mobile will be coming to Netflix gaming on November 6th.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/img_6333-1024x576.jpg" class="wp-image-112" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/img_6333-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/img_6333-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/img_6333-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/img_6333-1536x864.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/img_6333.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Netflix Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p>If you have a Netflix membership you can play the game via the Netflix mobile app, and you can also download the game from the App Store on IOS and Android and play if you’re logged into Netflix on the same device. </p>



<p>FM24 Mobile will not be available via Netflix on Smart TVs, PCs, Laptops and Games Consoles. </p>



<p>Football Manager 2024 releases everywhere November 6th.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/football-manager-is-coming-to-netflix/">Football Manager is coming to Netflix</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Making a Statement: How 1980s Football Shirts Embraced The Decade&#8217;s Style</title>
		<link>/how-1980s-football-shirts-embraced-the-decades-style/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-1980s-football-shirts-embraced-the-decades-style</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot Fagan-Briggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 15:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[#Style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1980s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adidas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Retro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Umbro]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=83</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Football shirts in the 1980s made a bold statement by embracing the audacious styles and culture of the decade. As synthetic fabrics replaced traditional cotton, kit designs moved into daring new territory with abstract graphics, geometric patterns and vivid neon hues. Teams pushed the boundaries with shirts in bright greens, electric pinks, and citrus yellows [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/how-1980s-football-shirts-embraced-the-decades-style/">Making a Statement: How 1980s Football Shirts Embraced The Decade&#8217;s Style</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Football shirts in the 1980s made a bold statement by embracing the audacious styles and culture of the decade.</strong> As synthetic fabrics replaced traditional cotton, kit designs moved into daring new territory with abstract graphics, geometric patterns and vivid neon hues. Teams pushed the boundaries with shirts in bright greens, electric pinks, and citrus yellows that exemplified 1980s flair. Loud designs like Belgium’s red and black geometric patterned home shirt from 1984 burn themselves into fans’ memories. Other kits made a statement with multicoloured zig-zags, paint-splatter motifs, and clashing blocks of colour. By borrowing themes from 80s fashion, music and pop culture, football shirts shed their traditional looks and captured the brash, larger-than-life vibe that defined the decade. This article will explore some of the most memorable and emblematic 1980s football shirts that seamlessly embraced the style of the times.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignwide size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="736" height="414" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/alan-ball-england-bobby-charlton-world-cup-final-west-germany_3395703.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-84" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/alan-ball-england-bobby-charlton-world-cup-final-west-germany_3395703.jpg 736w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/alan-ball-england-bobby-charlton-world-cup-final-west-germany_3395703-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 736px) 100vw, 736px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">England&#8217;s 1966 World Cup shirt epitomized the simple, cotton designs prevalent before the 1980s. Image via Sky Sports</figcaption></figure>



<p>Prior to the 1980s, football shirt design remained relatively traditional and understated. Most clubs wore simple stripes, blocks of colour, or the occasional monochrome look. Natural fibers like cotton, wool and linen were standard, limiting bold patterns and colours. However, the late 1970s saw synthetic fabrics like polyester emerge, allowing for more experimentation. Sportswear brands <a href="https://adidas.com/">Adidas</a>, <a href="https://umbro.com/">Umbro</a> and <a href="https://puma.com/">Puma</a> began developing shirts with bold new designs to suit the materials. By the 1980s, shirts moved further from their pedestrian roots with abstract graphics, daring geometrics and vivid neon palettes. New screen-printing and dyeing techniques opened up creative possibilities. As sponsors and brands became more prominent, they encouraged custom designs that made a statement. This intersection of sport, fashion and advertising in the 1980s propelled football shirts into uncharted visual territory.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Netherlands Adidas Home Shirt (1988)</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/netherlands-1988-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-86" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/netherlands-1988-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/netherlands-1988-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/netherlands-1988-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/netherlands-1988.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Netherlands Adidas Kit at the 1988 European Championships (Image via Screenshot from YouTube)</figcaption></figure>



<p>The abstract geometric patterns on the famous 1988 Netherlands Adidas home shirt captured the era&#8217;s avant-garde spirit. Its unusual ornate design in bright orange and white stood out on the pitch.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Barcelona Home Shirt (1982-89)</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="673" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/barcelona80s-1024x673.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-90" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/barcelona80s-1024x673.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/barcelona80s-300x197.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/barcelona80s-768x505.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/barcelona80s.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">FC Barcelona home shirt worn throughout the 1980&#8217;s (Image via https://www.topvintagefootballshirts.com/)</figcaption></figure>



<p>Barcelona&#8217;s shirt from <a href="https://www.meyba.com/">Meyba</a> with large red and blue vertical stripes became iconic of the decade. Few designs better capture Spanish flair and modern art influences.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">West Germany Home Shirt (1988)</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignwide size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="988" height="556" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/european_championship_germany_v_denmark-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-91" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/european_championship_germany_v_denmark-1.jpg 988w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/european_championship_germany_v_denmark-1-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/european_championship_germany_v_denmark-1-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 988px) 100vw, 988px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">West Germany 1988 Adidas Home Kit (Image via UEFA)</figcaption></figure>



<p>This patriotic home shirt from the 1988 Euros contained an abstract graphic print of the German flag which went with the Adidas branding. The visual embodied the country&#8217;s vibrant pop culture scene.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Fiorentina Home Shirt (1981-1983)</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignwide size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="575" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/fiorentina1982-1024x575.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-93" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/fiorentina1982-1024x575.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/fiorentina1982-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/fiorentina1982-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/fiorentina1982-1536x863.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/fiorentina1982.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Fiorentina Home Shirt in 1982 (Image via http://soccernostalgia.blogspot.com/)</figcaption></figure>



<p>The iconic purple home shirts made by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/jdfarrows/">J.D Farrow&#8217;s</a> featured a huge club badge on the front which style was repeated on the back for the player&#8217;s kit number. The bright red V-neck and collar also stand out.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Ajax Amsterdam Away Shirt (1989-90)</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="768" height="505" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/image.jpg" class="wp-image-110" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/image.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/image-300x197.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></figure>



<p>Ajax&#8217;s rare blue, red and white abstract away kit exemplified the novelty and creativity of the era. Its bold diamond design was a striking symbol of Dutch style.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The 80&#8217;s Style</h3>



<p>Several design motifs defined the bold new football aesthetic of the 1980s. Vibrant, eye-catching colours like bright yellow, neon pink, and electric blue replaced traditional shades. Striped, zig-zag, and abstract graphic prints brought art influences to the kits. Large geometric shapes and diagonal lines conveyed movement and energy. Stars, lightning bolts and other accents added striking details. Manufacturers like Adidas experimented with shoulder designs that extended across the chest. New technologies allowed for gradients, fades, and colour blending on fabric. These common elements came together to create shirts that perfectly aligned with music, fashion and culture in the 1980s. The decade proved that football kits could make provocative artistic statements beyond just team colours and logos.</p>



<p>The bold prints and colours of 1980s football shirts mirrored what was happening across music, fashion, and pop culture in the decade. Kits adopted the bright, neon palette that defined MTV music videos and new wave bands like The Police. Abstract shapes and patterns took inspiration from postmodern art and the Memphis Group furniture designers. Shoulder pad designs were borrowed straight from popular 80s fashions. The avant-garde, rule-breaking ethos of designers like Vivienne Westwood influenced shirts that broke conventions. Brand logos and sponsor placements grew driving commercial trends. Above all, the artful self-expression and experimentation that flourished in the 1980s as artists like Jean-Michel Basquiat redefined culture was embodied by football shirts adopting a similar groundbreaking spirit. The kits crossed over from sport into wider cultural style.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="413" height="620" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/Westwood.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-100"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Vivienne Westwood designs in the 1980s (Image via The Standard)</figcaption></figure>



<p>Star players and successful teams drove distinct shirt styles that fans wanted to emulate. Diego Maradona’s transfer to Napoli ignited demand for their light blue jerseys worldwide. Juventus’ Michel Platini wore the team’s iconic black and white stripes as he dominated Serie A. English clubs like Everton and Aston Villa gained international followings through European success, spreading their shirt designs globally. Real Madrid’s all-white look gained prestige as Hugo Sanchez starred for the club. For national teams, Brazilian great Socrates rocked an iconic yellow jersey that Pelé first popularized in the 1970s. On the club level, AC Milan’s Dutch trio Ruud Gullit, Marco van Basten and Frank Rijkaard made the red and black stripes fashionable. Whether through trophies, charisma or flashy styles, individual superstars and teams left an imprint on shirt trends during the decade.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/maradona.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-102" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/maradona.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/maradona-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/maradona-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Maradona in Napoli&#8217;s famous blue kit, 1988 (Image via BeSoccer)</figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignwide size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="599" height="402" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/BjR4iV9CMAAANvl.png" alt="" class="wp-image-103" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/BjR4iV9CMAAANvl.png 599w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/BjR4iV9CMAAANvl-300x201.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 599px) 100vw, 599px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Milan&#8217;s Dutch Trio (Image via 90s Football on X)</figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="597" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/unitedaway-1024x597.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-104" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/unitedaway-1024x597.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/unitedaway-300x175.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/unitedaway-768x448.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/unitedaway.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Norman Whiteside and Bryan Robson sporting Man United&#8217;s classic blue Adidas away kit (Image via DerryNow)</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Catapulting Kits into Pop Culture</h3>



<p>The rise of television broadcasts beaming matches into homes worldwide allowed kits to become bold fashion statements. As the sport gained more exposure, shirts adopted brighter palettes and abstract designs to stand out on the small screen. At the same time, corporate sponsorships on jerseys became more prominent. Brands like Coca-Cola, Adidas and Hitachi splashed their logos across shirt fronts, bringing commercialization. The need for shirts to function as both TV-friendly billboards for sponsors and visually striking team identifiers accelerated the artistic evolution. Loud colours, daring prints and prominent branding made kits pop on TV while giving brands coveted screen time. This synergy between television and sponsorships catapulted football shirts from athletic wear into mainstream pop culture.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="655" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/C-Wik1jXcAEuDf_-1024x655.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-107" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/C-Wik1jXcAEuDf_-1024x655.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/C-Wik1jXcAEuDf_-300x192.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/C-Wik1jXcAEuDf_-768x491.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/C-Wik1jXcAEuDf_-1536x983.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/C-Wik1jXcAEuDf_-2048x1310.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Liverpool&#8217;s 1981 home shirt with Hitachi as the sponsor (Image via Liverpool News on X)</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Back to the future</h3>



<p>Vintage 1980s shirt designs continue influencing the game today. Many clubs are marking anniversaries by bringing back classic designs from the decade. Liverpool recently revived their 1984-85 kit with the original Candy sponsor logo intact. Arsenal released a modern take on their famous yellow and blue zig-zag away strip from the early 90s. Tottenham incorporated their iconic &#8216;Holsten&#8217; sponsor logo across new merchandise. Barcelona and Real Madrid pay homage to 80s kits yearly through retro third jerseys. The vintage trend satisfies nostalgia while underscoring the era&#8217;s lasting cultural impact. 3D graphic prints and neon colours from the 1980s even appear on contemporary kits as a callback. Though recreated with modern fits and fabrics, the retro motif proves today’s designers still draw inspiration from the audacious creativity that defined 1980s shirts.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="481" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/united-originals-in-post-1024x481.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-108" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/united-originals-in-post-1024x481.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/united-originals-in-post-300x141.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/united-originals-in-post-768x361.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/united-originals-in-post-1536x721.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/united-originals-in-post.jpg 1704w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Manchester United and Adidas re-release their kit from the late 80&#8217;s (Image via Adidas UK)</figcaption></figure>



<p>The 1980s represented a transformative period for football kit design, when shirts evolved from plain athletic gear into bold pop culture statements. Advances in printing and fabrics allowed designers to experiment with dazzling colours, stripes, shapes and graphics that captured the decade’s avant-garde spirit. Players and teams left an indelible mark on shirt trends through their success and charisma. Television broadcasts and sponsorships accelerated kits shedding their traditional looks for innovative, artistic expression. The era produced some of the most recognizable and aesthetically daring jerseys in history, which still inspire nostalgia and retro revivals today. The 1980s proved football shirts could make provocative artistic statements far beyond just team colours and badges. The decade paved the way for today’s designers to treat kits as contemporary culture pieces rather than merely functional sporting apparel.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/how-1980s-football-shirts-embraced-the-decades-style/">Making a Statement: How 1980s Football Shirts Embraced The Decade&#8217;s Style</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 10 Best Football Documentaries to watch right now</title>
		<link>/top-10-football-documentaries-to-watch/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=top-10-football-documentaries-to-watch</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot Fagan-Briggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 19:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[#Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Documentaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=78</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>With gaps in the season, international breaks, and postponements in the football calendar, theres a lot of time when there might not be live football on TV, so why not watch some of the best football documentaries available right now. We&#8217;ve compiled a list of the&#160;10 best football documentaries&#160;available to watch online right now, through [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/top-10-football-documentaries-to-watch/">The 10 Best Football Documentaries to watch right now</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>With gaps in the season, international breaks, and postponements in the football calendar, theres a lot of time when there might not be live football on TV, so why not watch some of the best football documentaries available right now.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve compiled a list of the&nbsp;<strong>10 best football documentaries</strong>&nbsp;available to watch online right now, through various streaming services including&nbsp;<strong><em><a href="http://netflix.com/">Netflix</a></em></strong>,&nbsp;<strong><em><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Amazon-Video/">Amazon Prime</a></em></strong>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<strong><em><a href="https://www.disneyplus.com/home">Disney+</a></em></strong>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>1.</strong>&nbsp;<strong>The Figo Affair: The Transfer that Changed Football</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://transferrumourgenerator.online/images/figo.jpeg" alt="Figo"/></figure>



<p>How to watch:&nbsp;<strong>Netflix</strong></p>



<p>This 1 hour 44 minute documentary released in 2022 spotlights one of the most controversial deals in football history and the magnificent player at the centre of the storm: Luis Figo.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>2. Neymar: The Perfect Chaos</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://transferrumourgenerator.online/images/neymar.jpeg" alt="Neymar"/></figure>



<p>How to watch:&nbsp;<strong>Netflix</strong></p>



<p>This limited series produced by Netflix follows Neymar Jr. as he shares the highs and lows of the his personal life and football career, including his enormous rise from the streets of Brazil to the glamour of Paris.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>3. Rooney</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://transferrumourgenerator.online/images/rooney.jpeg" alt="Rooney"/></figure>



<p>How to watch:&nbsp;<strong>Amazon Prime</strong></p>



<p>Rooney is a captivating feature length documentary with unprecedented access to the life and career of a global but controversial footballing icon and arguably England’s greatest ever player.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>4. Welcome to Wrexham</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://transferrumourgenerator.online/images/wrexham.jpeg" alt="Welcome To Wrexham"/></figure>



<p>How to watch:&nbsp;<strong>Disney+</strong></p>



<p>Welcome to Wrexham documents Ryan Reynolds and Rob McElhenney&#8217;s acquisition of the worlds 3rd oldest football club, Wrexham AFC. The show makes for a great watch as the two Hollywood stars have no experience in how to run a football club. Season 2 releases in September 2023.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>5. All or Nothing: Arsenal</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://transferrumourgenerator.online/images/allornothing-arsenal.jpeg" alt="Arsenal"/></figure>



<p>How to watch:&nbsp;<strong>Amazon Prime</strong></p>



<p>All or Nothing: Arsenal follows the iconic North London football club during a season where they are expected to challenge for the top 4 but face the difficulties of COVID 19 and disruption within the squad. Can Manager Mikel Arteta cope with the pressure?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>6. Sir Alex Ferguson: Never Give In</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://transferrumourgenerator.online/images/fergie.jpeg" alt="Ferguson"/></figure>



<p>How to watch:&nbsp;<strong>Amazon Prime</strong></p>



<p>This revealing 2021 documentary is about one of the greatest managers of all time, Sir Alex Ferguson. While recovering from a brain haemorrhage, he details his life and career, including his incredible 26 years as manager of Manchester United.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>7. Arsene Wenger: Invincible</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://transferrumourgenerator.online/images/wenger.jpg" alt="Wenger"/></figure>



<p>How to watch:&nbsp;<strong>Amazon Prime</strong></p>



<p>Arsene Wenger: Invincible is the definitive portrait of the one the worlds greatest football managers. Featuring previously unseen footage and featuring a support cast of Sir Alex Ferguson, Thierry Henry and Ian Wright, this a must watch for any late 90’s, early 2000’s Premier League fan.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>8. Robbo: The Bryan Robson Story</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://transferrumourgenerator.online/images/robbo.jpeg" alt="Robbo"/></figure>



<p>How to watch:&nbsp;<strong>Amazon Prime</strong></p>



<p>Robbo is the remarkable feature length documentary that tells the story of the former England and Manchester United captain. It documents his life from his roots as a working-class kid in the North East to becoming a national icon.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>9. Galacticos</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://transferrumourgenerator.online/images/galacticos.jpeg" alt="Galacticos"/></figure>



<p>How to watch:&nbsp;<strong>Disney+</strong></p>



<p>A 3-part docuseries about Florentino Perez&#8217; first term as president of Real Madrid and the Galactico revolution which saw the club sign some of the worlds biggest names and featuing interviews with some of the legendary players that wore the famous white shirt.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>10. South of the River</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://transferrumourgenerator.online/images/south-of-the-river.jpeg" alt="South of the River"/></figure>



<p>How to watch:&nbsp;<strong>Netflix</strong></p>



<p>This docuseries tells the stories of young, high-profile footballers from South London, who beat the odds in their quest for international success. Featuring the likes of Rio Ferdinand, Jadon Sancho, Ademola Lookman and Tammy Abraham.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/top-10-football-documentaries-to-watch/">The 10 Best Football Documentaries to watch right now</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Forgotten Football Management Games of the 2000s</title>
		<link>/forgotten-football-manager-games/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=forgotten-football-manager-games</link>
					<comments>/forgotten-football-manager-games/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot Fagan-Briggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 14:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[#Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Football Manager]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=28</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Nowadays, if you want to play a football management game, the only real option you have is the Football Manager series, but back in the early 2000s there were a whole host of different football management games to choose from. You can also view this article in video format below Championship Manager The most similar [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/forgotten-football-manager-games/">The Forgotten Football Management Games of the 2000s</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="c3a5">Nowadays, if you want to play a football management game, the only real option you have is the <a href="https://www.footballmanager.com/">Football Manager</a> series, but back in the early 2000s there were a whole host of different football management games to choose from.</p>



<p id="b818">You can also view this article in video format below</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="The Football Manager Games You Didn&#039;t Know Existed" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yswYfilYYMI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="f63d">Championship Manager</h2>



<p id="35ca">The most similar game to Football Manager was of course Championship Manager. In fact, they started out as the same game until the developers, Sports Interactive, and the publishers, Eidos, split in 2003. Sports Interactive kept the game, engine and database and launched Football Manager whereas Eidos kept the name and paired up with a new development studio to continue making Championship Manager.</p>



<p id="7c88">The gameplay was very similar to the original game, but it didn’t quite match up to the familiar game that everyone already loved. It had a similar 2D match engine and even had a licensing deal with Adidas, but fans quickly started switching over to Football Manager.</p>



<p id="365a">After sales began to fall year after year, Eidos decided to pull the plug on Championship Manager, and after a failed Mobile-Only relaunch in the following decade, they finally gave up. The last full PC Championship Manager game was released in 2011, with the mobile game lasting 5 years before Championship Manager was cancelled for good.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="d37e">LMA Manager</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="LMA Manager 2007 Gameplay 2021 (PCSX2/MacBook Pro)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tu-fiixlv2U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p id="ef01">One of the most popular football management games of the 2000s was LMA Manager. The console focused game was easily available on the PS2 and offered a 3D match engine which Football Manager didn’t have at the time. The graphics were similar to that of FIFA and PES and this opened up the market to people who didn’t like the spreadsheet look and feel of Football Manager and Championship Manager.</p>



<p id="adc5">The game allowed you to build and upgrade your stadium, create your own team and even had a Match of the Day style highlight show with commentary from Gary Lineker himself.</p>



<p id="19f4">The game was canceled after the release of LMA Manager 2007 as the software the game ran on had issues with newer hardware, but LMA Manager will always remain a fond memory of players in the early 2000s and who could forget some of the great songs used in the intros to the games.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="fd1b">FIFA Manager</h2>



<p id="aa0b">FIFA Manager, or Total Club Manager as it was also called, was EA Sport’s attempt at entering the management simulation market. Utilising the game engine from their popular FIFA Football games, FIFA Manager offered fans something recognisable when playing, compared to the 2D match engine of Football Manager.</p>



<p id="33b4">A big thing for players of FIFA Manager was the official licenses the game had due to EA Sports deals with the FIFA organisation. Leagues and Clubs around the world had their official badges and kits, and the game used real player faces compared to other football management games who had very few official licenses.</p>



<p id="adf3">The game also had a sort of role playing element which allowed the player to spend their managers wages on things like houses, cars and other goods, even if they couldn’t actually do anything with them.</p>



<p id="89e7">EA Sports announced that after the release of FIFA Manager 2014 that they would be canceling the series after poor sales compared to Football Manager. Some fans of the game still play it though, with a small community providing seasonal updates each year so that the game lives on.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="caee">Pro Evolution Soccer Management</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-embed aligncenter is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="PES Manager Gameplay In 2023" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_WnqNaTqVTo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p id="03b0">Most people who played football games throughout the 2000s probably aren’t even aware there ever was a Pro Evolution Soccer Management game, but in 2006 Konami released their entry into the genre. The PS2 only release was supposed to rival FIFA Manager, just as Pro Evolution Soccer had been the main rival to the FIFA series, but only the 1 instalment was ever released.</p>



<p id="0e76">The game featured the same match engine as PES and shared the few official licenses that game had, but errors in spelling and a slow gameplay put players off. Pro Evolution Soccer Management did feature some role-playing aspects such as having to hire a secretary and having face to face meetings with various staff members and new signings but it wasn’t enough to challenge the already established football management franchises.</p>



<p id="2b40">Konami did release a mobile version of the game during the 2010s, which featured official licenses from various teams each season, but when they rebranded PES to eFootball, they decided to discontinue updates and remove it from the app store.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="748d">Let’s Make A Soccer Team!</h2>



<p id="9cbd">Probably the strangest feature on this list is Let’s Make a Soccer Team! The game was more like a football club chairman simulator but did let you control the tactics of the team as well. It was very similar to Pro Evolution Soccer Management in how it looked and played, and released in Europe in 2006 as an adaptation of a Japanese game.</p>



<p id="9153">Let’s Make a Soccer Team! was unlike all the other games available in the fact that it had a storyline, in which you had an antagonist who was the chairman of a rival club and who you came across throughout the game. You also couldn’t manage a real club in the game, hence the title. The start of the game also made you take part in a play-off, and if you lost you had to start again, which annoyed players because you couldn’t just instantly start like the other football management games.</p>



<p id="0b57">Only the single instalment was ever released, as publishers SEGA, who also publish Football Manager, decided to focus on the already popular franchise instead of publishing new competitors.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/forgotten-football-manager-games/">The Forgotten Football Management Games of the 2000s</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/forgotten-football-manager-games/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
