<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Adidas Archives - FCP</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/adidas/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/adidas/</link>
	<description>Football Culture</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 11:05:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/logo2-150x150.png</url>
	<title>Adidas Archives - FCP</title>
	<link>/tag/adidas/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Stormzy brings back Merky FC for a new season</title>
		<link>/stormzy-brings-back-merky-fc-for-a-new-season/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=stormzy-brings-back-merky-fc-for-a-new-season</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot Fagan-Briggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 10:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[#Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adidas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merky FC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stormzy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Stormzy has once again teamed up with adidas to launch #Merky FC Football Careers Season 2, an initiative aimed at creating leadership opportunities in football for the Black community. The program was originally created in response to the fact that currently only 6.7% of leadership positions in football are held by those with Black heritage. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/stormzy-brings-back-merky-fc-for-a-new-season/">Stormzy brings back Merky FC for a new season</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Stormzy has once again teamed up with adidas to launch #Merky FC Football Careers Season 2, an initiative aimed at creating leadership opportunities in football for the Black community.</strong></p>



<p>The program was originally created in response to the fact that currently only 6.7% of leadership positions in football are held by those with Black heritage. Through <a href="https://merkyfc.com/">#Merky FC Football Careers</a>, Stormzy and adidas hope to address the lack of fair access and representation for Black individuals looking to build careers in the sport.</p>



<p>The multi-year partnership will provide a career development program and job placements across various roles in football, at various businesses including professional football clubs and media outlets.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignwide size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="670" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/IMG_6603-1024x670.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-153" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/IMG_6603-1024x670.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/IMG_6603-300x196.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/IMG_6603-768x503.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/10/IMG_6603.jpg 1170w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The brands and businesses working with Adidas and Merky FC this year</figcaption></figure>



<p>The first season of placements under #Merky FC Football Careers launched in November 2022 with 11 major brands participating. 15 Young black people from the UK earned jobs in the football industry as a result of Merky FC, and this year the second season will kick off in October 2023 with over 50 new placement opportunities.</p>



<p>Stormzy said &#8220;There&#8217;s still a massive gap in representation off the pitch&#8221;. He hopes the program will &#8220;create long-lasting change&#8221; and build a pipeline of future Black leaders in football. <a href="https://www.adidas.co.uk/football">Adidas</a> emphasized the importance of diversity and equal representation at all levels of the sport.</p>



<p>The initiative is the latest effort by Stormzy and adidas to increase inclusion and accessibility in football. Both have been outspoken advocates for racial equality in sport and society.</p>



<p>Watch the video below:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed aligncenter is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Merky?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Merky</a> FC is back, but this year, we&#39;ve got to go bigger.<br><br>Share one of the 50 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MerkyFC?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MerkyFC</a> roles with a friend now to change the game. <a href="https://t.co/pllMjqO5zv">https://t.co/pllMjqO5zv</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/adidasfootball?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@adidasfootball</a> <a href="https://t.co/qXSodEy07V">pic.twitter.com/qXSodEy07V</a></p>&mdash; Stormzy (@stormzy) <a href="https://twitter.com/stormzy/status/1709846452342501827?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2023</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="/stormzy-brings-back-merky-fc-for-a-new-season/">Stormzy brings back Merky FC for a new season</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Making a Statement: How 1980s Football Shirts Embraced The Decade&#8217;s Style</title>
		<link>/how-1980s-football-shirts-embraced-the-decades-style/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-1980s-football-shirts-embraced-the-decades-style</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot Fagan-Briggs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 15:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[#Style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1980s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adidas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Retro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Umbro]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=83</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Football shirts in the 1980s made a bold statement by embracing the audacious styles and culture of the decade. As synthetic fabrics replaced traditional cotton, kit designs moved into daring new territory with abstract graphics, geometric patterns and vivid neon hues. Teams pushed the boundaries with shirts in bright greens, electric pinks, and citrus yellows [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="/how-1980s-football-shirts-embraced-the-decades-style/">Making a Statement: How 1980s Football Shirts Embraced The Decade&#8217;s Style</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Football shirts in the 1980s made a bold statement by embracing the audacious styles and culture of the decade.</strong> As synthetic fabrics replaced traditional cotton, kit designs moved into daring new territory with abstract graphics, geometric patterns and vivid neon hues. Teams pushed the boundaries with shirts in bright greens, electric pinks, and citrus yellows that exemplified 1980s flair. Loud designs like Belgium’s red and black geometric patterned home shirt from 1984 burn themselves into fans’ memories. Other kits made a statement with multicoloured zig-zags, paint-splatter motifs, and clashing blocks of colour. By borrowing themes from 80s fashion, music and pop culture, football shirts shed their traditional looks and captured the brash, larger-than-life vibe that defined the decade. This article will explore some of the most memorable and emblematic 1980s football shirts that seamlessly embraced the style of the times.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignwide size-full"><img decoding="async" width="736" height="414" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/alan-ball-england-bobby-charlton-world-cup-final-west-germany_3395703.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-84" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/alan-ball-england-bobby-charlton-world-cup-final-west-germany_3395703.jpg 736w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/alan-ball-england-bobby-charlton-world-cup-final-west-germany_3395703-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 736px) 100vw, 736px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">England&#8217;s 1966 World Cup shirt epitomized the simple, cotton designs prevalent before the 1980s. Image via Sky Sports</figcaption></figure>



<p>Prior to the 1980s, football shirt design remained relatively traditional and understated. Most clubs wore simple stripes, blocks of colour, or the occasional monochrome look. Natural fibers like cotton, wool and linen were standard, limiting bold patterns and colours. However, the late 1970s saw synthetic fabrics like polyester emerge, allowing for more experimentation. Sportswear brands <a href="https://adidas.com/">Adidas</a>, <a href="https://umbro.com/">Umbro</a> and <a href="https://puma.com/">Puma</a> began developing shirts with bold new designs to suit the materials. By the 1980s, shirts moved further from their pedestrian roots with abstract graphics, daring geometrics and vivid neon palettes. New screen-printing and dyeing techniques opened up creative possibilities. As sponsors and brands became more prominent, they encouraged custom designs that made a statement. This intersection of sport, fashion and advertising in the 1980s propelled football shirts into uncharted visual territory.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Netherlands Adidas Home Shirt (1988)</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/netherlands-1988-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-86" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/netherlands-1988-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/netherlands-1988-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/netherlands-1988-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/netherlands-1988.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Netherlands Adidas Kit at the 1988 European Championships (Image via Screenshot from YouTube)</figcaption></figure>



<p>The abstract geometric patterns on the famous 1988 Netherlands Adidas home shirt captured the era&#8217;s avant-garde spirit. Its unusual ornate design in bright orange and white stood out on the pitch.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Barcelona Home Shirt (1982-89)</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="673" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/barcelona80s-1024x673.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-90" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/barcelona80s-1024x673.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/barcelona80s-300x197.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/barcelona80s-768x505.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/barcelona80s.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">FC Barcelona home shirt worn throughout the 1980&#8217;s (Image via https://www.topvintagefootballshirts.com/)</figcaption></figure>



<p>Barcelona&#8217;s shirt from <a href="https://www.meyba.com/">Meyba</a> with large red and blue vertical stripes became iconic of the decade. Few designs better capture Spanish flair and modern art influences.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">West Germany Home Shirt (1988)</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignwide size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="988" height="556" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/european_championship_germany_v_denmark-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-91" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/european_championship_germany_v_denmark-1.jpg 988w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/european_championship_germany_v_denmark-1-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/european_championship_germany_v_denmark-1-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 988px) 100vw, 988px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">West Germany 1988 Adidas Home Kit (Image via UEFA)</figcaption></figure>



<p>This patriotic home shirt from the 1988 Euros contained an abstract graphic print of the German flag which went with the Adidas branding. The visual embodied the country&#8217;s vibrant pop culture scene.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Fiorentina Home Shirt (1981-1983)</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignwide size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="575" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/fiorentina1982-1024x575.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-93" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/fiorentina1982-1024x575.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/fiorentina1982-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/fiorentina1982-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/fiorentina1982-1536x863.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/08/fiorentina1982.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Fiorentina Home Shirt in 1982 (Image via http://soccernostalgia.blogspot.com/)</figcaption></figure>



<p>The iconic purple home shirts made by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/jdfarrows/">J.D Farrow&#8217;s</a> featured a huge club badge on the front which style was repeated on the back for the player&#8217;s kit number. The bright red V-neck and collar also stand out.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Ajax Amsterdam Away Shirt (1989-90)</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="768" height="505" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/image.jpg" class="wp-image-110" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/image.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/image-300x197.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></figure>



<p>Ajax&#8217;s rare blue, red and white abstract away kit exemplified the novelty and creativity of the era. Its bold diamond design was a striking symbol of Dutch style.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The 80&#8217;s Style</h3>



<p>Several design motifs defined the bold new football aesthetic of the 1980s. Vibrant, eye-catching colours like bright yellow, neon pink, and electric blue replaced traditional shades. Striped, zig-zag, and abstract graphic prints brought art influences to the kits. Large geometric shapes and diagonal lines conveyed movement and energy. Stars, lightning bolts and other accents added striking details. Manufacturers like Adidas experimented with shoulder designs that extended across the chest. New technologies allowed for gradients, fades, and colour blending on fabric. These common elements came together to create shirts that perfectly aligned with music, fashion and culture in the 1980s. The decade proved that football kits could make provocative artistic statements beyond just team colours and logos.</p>



<p>The bold prints and colours of 1980s football shirts mirrored what was happening across music, fashion, and pop culture in the decade. Kits adopted the bright, neon palette that defined MTV music videos and new wave bands like The Police. Abstract shapes and patterns took inspiration from postmodern art and the Memphis Group furniture designers. Shoulder pad designs were borrowed straight from popular 80s fashions. The avant-garde, rule-breaking ethos of designers like Vivienne Westwood influenced shirts that broke conventions. Brand logos and sponsor placements grew driving commercial trends. Above all, the artful self-expression and experimentation that flourished in the 1980s as artists like Jean-Michel Basquiat redefined culture was embodied by football shirts adopting a similar groundbreaking spirit. The kits crossed over from sport into wider cultural style.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="413" height="620" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/Westwood.gif" alt="" class="wp-image-100"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Vivienne Westwood designs in the 1980s (Image via The Standard)</figcaption></figure>



<p>Star players and successful teams drove distinct shirt styles that fans wanted to emulate. Diego Maradona’s transfer to Napoli ignited demand for their light blue jerseys worldwide. Juventus’ Michel Platini wore the team’s iconic black and white stripes as he dominated Serie A. English clubs like Everton and Aston Villa gained international followings through European success, spreading their shirt designs globally. Real Madrid’s all-white look gained prestige as Hugo Sanchez starred for the club. For national teams, Brazilian great Socrates rocked an iconic yellow jersey that Pelé first popularized in the 1970s. On the club level, AC Milan’s Dutch trio Ruud Gullit, Marco van Basten and Frank Rijkaard made the red and black stripes fashionable. Whether through trophies, charisma or flashy styles, individual superstars and teams left an imprint on shirt trends during the decade.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/maradona.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-102" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/maradona.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/maradona-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/maradona-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Maradona in Napoli&#8217;s famous blue kit, 1988 (Image via BeSoccer)</figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignwide size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="599" height="402" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/BjR4iV9CMAAANvl.png" alt="" class="wp-image-103" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/BjR4iV9CMAAANvl.png 599w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/BjR4iV9CMAAANvl-300x201.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 599px) 100vw, 599px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Milan&#8217;s Dutch Trio (Image via 90s Football on X)</figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="597" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/unitedaway-1024x597.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-104" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/unitedaway-1024x597.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/unitedaway-300x175.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/unitedaway-768x448.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/unitedaway.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Norman Whiteside and Bryan Robson sporting Man United&#8217;s classic blue Adidas away kit (Image via DerryNow)</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Catapulting Kits into Pop Culture</h3>



<p>The rise of television broadcasts beaming matches into homes worldwide allowed kits to become bold fashion statements. As the sport gained more exposure, shirts adopted brighter palettes and abstract designs to stand out on the small screen. At the same time, corporate sponsorships on jerseys became more prominent. Brands like Coca-Cola, Adidas and Hitachi splashed their logos across shirt fronts, bringing commercialization. The need for shirts to function as both TV-friendly billboards for sponsors and visually striking team identifiers accelerated the artistic evolution. Loud colours, daring prints and prominent branding made kits pop on TV while giving brands coveted screen time. This synergy between television and sponsorships catapulted football shirts from athletic wear into mainstream pop culture.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="655" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/C-Wik1jXcAEuDf_-1024x655.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-107" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/C-Wik1jXcAEuDf_-1024x655.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/C-Wik1jXcAEuDf_-300x192.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/C-Wik1jXcAEuDf_-768x491.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/C-Wik1jXcAEuDf_-1536x983.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/C-Wik1jXcAEuDf_-2048x1310.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Liverpool&#8217;s 1981 home shirt with Hitachi as the sponsor (Image via Liverpool News on X)</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Back to the future</h3>



<p>Vintage 1980s shirt designs continue influencing the game today. Many clubs are marking anniversaries by bringing back classic designs from the decade. Liverpool recently revived their 1984-85 kit with the original Candy sponsor logo intact. Arsenal released a modern take on their famous yellow and blue zig-zag away strip from the early 90s. Tottenham incorporated their iconic &#8216;Holsten&#8217; sponsor logo across new merchandise. Barcelona and Real Madrid pay homage to 80s kits yearly through retro third jerseys. The vintage trend satisfies nostalgia while underscoring the era&#8217;s lasting cultural impact. 3D graphic prints and neon colours from the 1980s even appear on contemporary kits as a callback. Though recreated with modern fits and fabrics, the retro motif proves today’s designers still draw inspiration from the audacious creativity that defined 1980s shirts.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="481" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/united-originals-in-post-1024x481.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-108" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/united-originals-in-post-1024x481.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/united-originals-in-post-300x141.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/united-originals-in-post-768x361.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/united-originals-in-post-1536x721.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/united-originals-in-post.jpg 1704w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Manchester United and Adidas re-release their kit from the late 80&#8217;s (Image via Adidas UK)</figcaption></figure>



<p>The 1980s represented a transformative period for football kit design, when shirts evolved from plain athletic gear into bold pop culture statements. Advances in printing and fabrics allowed designers to experiment with dazzling colours, stripes, shapes and graphics that captured the decade’s avant-garde spirit. Players and teams left an indelible mark on shirt trends through their success and charisma. Television broadcasts and sponsorships accelerated kits shedding their traditional looks for innovative, artistic expression. The era produced some of the most recognizable and aesthetically daring jerseys in history, which still inspire nostalgia and retro revivals today. The 1980s proved football shirts could make provocative artistic statements far beyond just team colours and badges. The decade paved the way for today’s designers to treat kits as contemporary culture pieces rather than merely functional sporting apparel.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/how-1980s-football-shirts-embraced-the-decades-style/">Making a Statement: How 1980s Football Shirts Embraced The Decade&#8217;s Style</a> appeared first on <a href="/">FCP</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
